老妈 快点 我还得上学呢
Mom, come on, I need to get to school!
今天不是高四逃课日吗
Isn't it today Senior Ditch Day?
今天是逃课日吗
Today's Ditch Day?
逃课日你绝对不能错过
No way you are ditching Ditch Day.
这是高四最棒的一周...一天
It's like the best week of senior year...day.
不像我们家
Unlike this house,
图书馆会非常安静
the library will be completely quiet
我就可以专心选室友了
So I can focus on my roommate selection.
选一个书呆子舍友能花多少时间
How long can picking a nerdy roommate take?
她们就是你的不同版本罢了
They're all versions of you.
印度版的你 金发版的你 亚裔版的你
Look -- Indian you, blonde you, Asian you.
快看 她的名字就叫钰[音同你]
Oh, look! Her name is actually "Yu".
逃一天课不会怎么样的
Skipping one day of school isn't gonna do any harm.
我就逃了很多课 看看我现在
I ditched plenty, and look at me today.
我得到了很多工作机会
I am fielding multiple job offers.
只有一个
One job offer.
是一个著名的连锁酒店
From a very prominent hotel chain
我要在它和现在的工作之间权衡
weighed against the implied offer of staying at my current job.
现在的工作是给你爸打工
Working for you dad.
没错 而我不能离开外公
Exactly! And I could never leave grandpa,
所以我要拒绝第一个工作机会
so I am going to say "No" to the first offer --
唯一一个
Only offer.
即便我完全可以胜任
Even though I would have made an excellent
分管销售的地区副总裁职务
regional vice president in charge of promotions.
她确实很擅长推销
She is great at promotion.
那职位名被她越说越长了
That title gets longer every time I hear it.
拜托 别去学校了
Come on, don't go to school.
姐妹日 我们一起去逛商场
Girls' day! We'll swing by the mall.
你的全身衣物都需要换新的了
You could use a new everything.
姑娘们 快上车 卢克受伤了
Girls, get in the car. Luke's hurt.
天呐 发生了什么
Oh, my God. What happened?
他上学路上晕倒了
He collapsed on the way to school.
现在在医院里 快点
He's in the hospital. Come on.
卢克怎么了 他怎么会晕倒
What's wrong with Luke? Why'd he collapsed?
我听说他死了
I heard he was dead!
原来你们这么关心我
You care about me.
把她们耍得团团转 伙计
Got 'em good, buddy.
没人死了
Nobody's dead!
-小心 -对不起
- Look out! - Oh, sorry!
你疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?!
艾丽克斯 你这一年简直学疯了
Alex, you have worked so insanely hard this year.
你比任何人都该享受逃课日
You deserve this Ditch Day more than anyone.
所以你猜怎么着
So guess what?
我们要去加州冒险乐园[迪士尼乐园]
We're going to California Adventure.
不带老妈
Without mom!
逃课日 逃课日 逃课日
Ditch Day! Ditch Day! Ditch Day!
这是你们的什么盛大节日吗
Is this a high holiday for you people?
没错 我下定决心了
That's it. I'm doing it.
我要把所有的袜子都扔掉 重新开始
I'm throwing out all my socks and starting over.
他们还说蒂娜离开艾克很勇敢
And they say Tina was brave for leaving Ike.
天呐 好疼
Oh, God. That hurts.
天呐 你切到自己了
Oh, my Gosh. You cut yourself.
血可别流到我的蛋里
Don't get blood in my eggs.
我们越来越担心
We're getting concerned
莉莉似乎不是很有同情心
that Lily hasn't developed an adequate sense of empathy.
应该说是完全没有
Insofar as she doesn't have any at all.
好吧 很好 感觉好像有用
Okay, that's good. I can feel that working.
是啊 终于可以呼吸了
I know. I can finally breathe.
吵得我都无法思考了
I can't hear myself think!
完全可以预见到我们的暮年生活
Nice preview of our sunset years.
她直接把我们的插头[呼吸机]拔掉了
She literally pulled the plug on us.
我没打算告诉我爸另一个工作机会的事
I wasn't gonna mention the other job offer to my dad,
但我也不想他从别人那里知道
but I didn't want him just hearing about it,
所以在纠结一天后 我决定告诉他
so after wrestling with it all day, I decided to tell him.
你来得真早啊
Hey, you're in early.
你想听个笑话吗
Are you ready to have a laugh?
杰妮斯的发型吗
Janice's haircut?
别太难为她啦
Give her some slack.
她刚刚分手...
She just went through a breakup...
估计是跟个女的 我看她发型猜的
with a woman, I assume, based on the haircut.
不 其实更有意思
No, it's even funnier.
你知道我一直在努力争取
Uh, so you know how hard I've been working on
皇家大饭店这个客户吧
the Grand Royal Hotel account?
想加薪等明年吧 不过你继续说
Not giving raises till next year, but go on.
他们请我去工作
They offered me a job.
很意外 对吧
Crazy, right?
-是啊 -是啊
- Yeah. - Yeah.
也不是完全意外
I mean, maybe not "crazy",
但是居然想挖走老板的女儿
but trying to poach the boss's daughter?
我一定是给他们留下了深刻印象
I must have impressed 'em.
你得接受这份工作
You gotta take this offer.
什么
What?
工资更高 福利更好
Higher salary, better benefits.
你可能得经常出差
I mean, you might have to travel more,
意味着要时不时离开菲尔
which is time away from Phil.
全是好处
Nothing but upside.
他说得对
He was right.
确实是个大好的机会
It was a great opportunity.
那个工作机会
I may have been a bit hasty
我可能拒绝得太急了
turning down that job offer so quickly.
可以给我一两天时间考虑一下吗
Do you think you could give me a day or two to think about it?
是 这意味着我得离开我爸
Yes, it would mean leaving my dad,
但这是生意场
but this was business.
跟私人感情无关
It wasn't personal.
而且 我爸显然不在乎我的死活
Plus, clearly my father doesn't care if I live or die.
没了智齿 我还有智慧吗
Hey, will I still get wise without my wisdom teeth?
-听懂了吗 -都懂啦
- You get it? - Every time.
把止痛片给我吧
Why don't I hold on to the painkillers?
现在我很难过
Now I'm sad.
就在这里
They're right here.
你想要时我就给你
I'll give you one when you need one.
不 凯莉说她会在牙医那里等我
No, Kylie said she'd meet me at the dentist
但她没来
and she never came.
我知道 宝贝儿 很遗憾
Ay, I know, Papi, I'm so sorry,
我去你卧室里把你的枕头拿来
but I'm gonna get you a very nice pillow from your bedroom.
她想让我这个夏天陪她去戏剧夏令营
She wants me to go away with her to drama camp this summer,
然而她今天都不肯来吗
And then she doesn't even show up today?
也许凯莉改变主意了
Maybe Kylie changed her mind about camp.
也许她想跟很多人交往
Maybe she plans to be with many men
她配不上你
and she doesn't deserve you.
曼尼完全看不出来
I hid it very well from Manny,
但我真的很讨厌那姑娘
but I hated that girl.
她和曼尼发展得太快太认真了
She was getting too serious too fast.
我好抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我的排球训练延时了
My volleyball practice went long
然后我的手机没电了
and then my phone died.
我想吻你 但我嘴里一股药味
I want to kiss you, but I have surgery breath.
你要快点回到可以亲吻的状态
Just make sure you're back in kissing shape
我们一起参加夏令营时就能亲亲了
in time for us to go to camp together.
我为什么一直闻到草莓的味道
Why do I keep smelling strawberries?
他们对我做了什么
What did they do to me?
是我给你带来的奶昔啦
It's the milkshake I brought you.
瞧瞧
Oh, and look.
我一般都等你没注意的时候才偷看
I usually wait till you're not looking, then I look.
是说你送人家的围巾 讨厌了啦
The scarf you gave me, you dog!
实际上 现在是观看的好时机
Actually, now's a good time to look
因为我看到了四个
'cause I kinda see four of them.
我吃了几片药
I got a couple pills in me.
逃课日 逃课日 逃课日
Ditch Day. Ditch Day. Ditch Day.
逃课...
Ditch...
15分钟
15 minutes.
连加油的时候你们都没停
When you didn't stop while we were getting gas,
我还以为你们会一直喊下去呢
I thought it might just go on forever.
天啊
Sweet Myrna Loy!
爸爸 你知道放的不是
Dad, you know it's not
一部名叫《拆迁公告》的电影 对吧
a movie called "Demolition Notice", right?
我靠自己的双手建造了这个影院...
I built this theater with these two hands...
还有其余14个人的28只手
plus the 28 hands of 14 other guys.
就你 建造的
You...built this.
我整修的
Renovated it.
进入房地产界之前我在建筑业工作
Before I got into real estate, I worked construction.
就你 在建筑业工作
You....worked construction.
是的 别那样说话
Yeah, stop staying it like that.
我为这地方消耗了10个月心血
I put 10 months of my life into this place.
我很想在他们拆掉这栋建筑前
I'd love to look around one last time
最后看看这里
before they tear the old girl down.
变老真糟糕
Oh, well, sucks to be getting old.
我们要闯进去
You know what? We're bustin' in.
怎么做啊 用砖头砸窗户吗
How? Smash a window with a brick?
我想到了更为优雅的办法
I had something a little more elegant in mind.
我想你们忘记了 是我建造了这栋大楼
I think you forget that I gave birth to this building.
我知道她的长处
I know her strengths...
和弱点
and... her weaknesses.
你们有看到砖头吗
Did you see a brick?
我走进老爸的办公室
So I walked into to Dad's office,
他拿着我的照片
and he is holding a picture of me,
满眼含泪地看着
looking at it with tears welling in his eyes.
我们小时候老爸从来没有这么多愁善感
Oh, Dad was never that emotional when we were growing up.
就是啊 所以这事才这么难办
I know. That's what makes this whole thing so hard!
也许莉莉没学到同情
Maybe lily hasn't learned empathy
是因为没看见我表现出同情心
because she hasn't seen it from me, you know?
我们能在上面包之前先专注于我的问题吗
Could we maybe stay on my problem until the bread comes?
对不起 听起来你好像是说完了
I'm sorry. It sounded like you were done. Sorry.
我跟酒店那边说的是
So, the way I left things with the hotel company
我还需要一点时间来考虑
is that I need a little more time to decide,
但是说真的 我打算拒绝他们
but honestly, I think I'm gonna tell 'em no.
看见那一幕之后我怎么能离开老爸
I mean, how could I leave Dad after what I saw?
真是令人心碎
It's just -- it's heartbreaking.
我都快哭了
Oh, I could cry.
谢谢
Thank you.
也许如果莉莉看见我哭
Maybe if Lily saw me cry,
她就会觉得哭也没关系
she would see that it's okay to be that way,
特别是看见我这个从来不哭的坚忍老爸哭
especially coming from me, her stoic dad who never cries.
拜托 你刚才肯定说完了啊
Oh, come on, you had to be done that time.
知道吗 你说得对 说你的事吧
You know what? You're right. Let's do you.
反正你的问题比我的更大
Your problem is bigger than mine anyway,
因为如果你的计划是在莉莉面前哭
'cause if your plan is to cry in front of Lily...
算了吧
Forget it.
你情感上太冷漠了
You're too emotionally constipated.
我知道你在开玩笑 克莱尔
You know, I-I know you're joking, Claire,
但是有时候言语会伤人
but sometimes... sometimes words hurt, you know?
一想起我的亲姐姐...
And to think that my own sister...
我的亲姐姐会说我 算了吧
my own sister would accuse me of -- Oh, screw it.
我就看一部悲剧电影来催泪吧 没关系
I'll just work up some tears with a sad movie. It's fine.
妈妈
Mom?
你醒了啊
You're awake.
你感觉怎么样
How you feeling?
你给我买了个气球
You bought me a balloon.
-什么 -还有泰迪熊
- What? - And a teddy bear.
你什么时候买的
When did you buy all this stuff?
你睡觉的时候
When -- when you were asleep
我还给你买了草莓奶昔
and I got you a strawberry milkshake.
世上只有妈妈好
Mom, you're the best.
他什么都不记得了
He couldn't remember a thing.
我只要拖住他到五点报名截止
All I had to do was to get him past the 5:00 deadline
这样他就没法和凯莉一起出行了
so that he couldn't go on that trip with Kylie.
我知道在夏令营会发生什么
I know what happens at camp.
我看过《疯狂夏令营》
I've seen "Meatballs".
我还是难以相信凯莉放了我鸽子
I still can't believe Kylie flaked on me.
我还以为她真的很喜欢我
I thought she really liked me.
我想不是吧
I guess not.
又该吃药了 宝贝
Time for more pills, baby.
真的吗 我已经很晕了
Really? I'm already so loopy.
得在感觉到疼之前就吃
We have to get ahead of the pain.
也许她给我发了短信
Maybe she texted me.
你看见我的手机了吗
Have you seen my phone?
不是在那里吗
Is it over there?
我没看见
I don't see it.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
拥抱你
Eh...hugging!
你真贴心
You're so sweet.
但我觉得这些药没效果
But I don't think these pills are really doing anything.
这地方看起来眼熟吗
Does this place look familiar?
是的 我们就是在这里被谋杀的
Oh, yeah. This is where we were all murdered.
不 你们姐妹就是在这看的第一部电影
No, silly. This is where you girls saw your first movie.
《兔八哥之夜》放了一半时
Halfway through "Hare-Abian Nights",
我往旁边看去 你们的小脑袋挤在一起
I looked over, and your little heads were pressed together
像是可爱的小圆锥帐篷
like the cutest teepee ever.
全家人找乐子时我在哪里
And where was I during all of this family fun?
小子 我们仨当时在过女生之日呢
Buddy, the three of us were having a girls' day.
你懂的
You get it.
这边 屏幕这里
This way. Over here by the screen.
话说
So...
我还在建造这里时
while I was still building this place,
有天下班后 我和你们一起偷偷溜回来
I snuck back here with you guys after work one day, and...
瞧瞧看
check it out.
爸爸 那是我们的脚印吗
Aw, dad! Are those our feet?
瞧瞧有多小
Look at how tiny!
我的脚印呢
Where's my footprints?
我猜这个是你的
Um... I guess that's you. Anyway...
那看起来像个婴儿的脑袋印
That looks like a baby head.
这俩丫头我都忙不过来
I was struggling with these two.
加上你一直扭个不停
You were all squirmy.
我都道过很多次歉了
I'm not gonna apologize over and over.
来吧 我们拿上这个
Come on, let's grab this thing.
拿什么 水泥吗
Grab what, the cement?
这地方过几天就要变成一片废墟了
This place is gonna be rubble in a few days.
我想要留点回忆
I want a memento.
行动吧
Let's do it!
这个看起来比较像男孩子的工作
All right, well, this seems more like boys' work,
你们慢慢玩哦
so you guys take your time on that, okay?
真是超棒的探险
Super fun adventure!
他们至少要花一个小时
Okay, so that's at least an hour.
马路对面有家商场
There's a mall across the street.
我打电话叫车 现在去学校
I'm calling a car and going to school.
加州理工要我尽快选好室友
Caltech needs my roommate selection by --
你到底怎么了
What's your problem?
你怎么了 你不跟老爸说一声就要走吗
What's yours? You're just gonna leave without telling Dad?
你不是还要带我去商场吗
You were just about to take me to a mall.
好吧 你看不出区别就算了
Okay, if you can't see the difference...
抱歉 比起逛街或者坐在一间
Look, I'm sorry I've got better things to do
我们过去看动画片的破影院里
than go shop or sit in some creepy old movie theater
我还有更重要的事情做
Where we used to watch cartoons.
我知道 你比我们都厉害多了
I get it. You're beyond all of us now.
快去挑你的书呆子学院小伙伴吧
Go pick out your playmates at nerd academy.
好吧
Fine.
我就在这里挑室友好了
I'll just pick out my roommate here then.
抱歉我对上大学的事太激动了
Sorry I'm so excited about college.
我不接受道歉
Apology not accepted.
反正我也没想真道歉
I wasn't actually apologizing, so...
找到灯了
Found the light!
找到凿子了
Found the chisel!
找到扫把了
Found the broom.
不 不
No, no.
米奇尔 出什么事了
Mitchell? What's wrong?
我觉得莉莉对人这么冷漠
I feel like Lily's inability to show feelings
可能是我的错
for other people might be my fault.
亲爱的
Oh, honey.
我也这么觉得 不过至少
I think that, too, but just take comfort in knowing
你自己意识到了
you got there on your own.
我在看《廊桥遗梦》
I'm watching "The Bridges of Madison County"
因为这是唯一能弄哭我的
because it's the only thing that makes me cry.
等她回家了
When she gets home,
我会关掉电视假装我在读这个
I'm going to turn this off and pretend I was reading this.
《台风荡平孤儿院》
"Typhoon Flattens Orphanage"?
很悲伤的故事吧
Yeah, that's sad, right?
现在 你快走
Now -- now get out of here,
她随时可能回来
because she's going to be home any second,
我得努力维持悲伤的状态
and I'm trying to stay sad.
等等 等等 我想问清楚
Wait. Wait, wait, wait, wait. Just to clarify,
唯一能弄哭你的
the only thing that makes you cry...
能真正在情感上让你产生共鸣的
that truly resonates with you on a deep, emotional level
是一部关于陷入无爱婚姻之苦的电影吗
is a film about someone... who's trapped in a loveless marriage?
好了 小卡 请快走
Okay, Cam, please go.
我已经开始出戏了
I'm starting not to feel anything.
你知道那有多伤人吗
Do you know how hurtful that is?
我回来了
I'm home!
我现在哭不下去了 真棒
And now I'm not crying. Great.
亲爱的 你今天过得怎么样
Hey, sweetie. Hi. How was your day?
比她过得好 发生什么事了
Better than hers. What's wrong now?
大爸有点小情绪
Daddy's just having a moment.
他总是有小情绪
He's always having a moment.
等等 天呐 我刚发现一件事
Oh, wait. Oh, my gosh. I-I just realized something.
怎么 你发现我们的婚床
What, that our marriage bed
是个1200针的无爱摆设吗
is a 1,200 thread-count charade?
不 这可能不是我的错
No, maybe this isn't my fault.
也许莉莉没有同情心是因为你老是哭
Maybe Lily can't show empathy because you're always crying.
-所以怪我咯 -对
- Oh, so it's my fault? - Yes.
你害她对正常的情感麻木了
You've totally desensitized her to normal emotions.
才没有
That's not true!
而且你现在很想哭
And now you wanna cry,
因为她因为你总是哭而从来不哭
because she won't cry because you're always crying.
然而你会知道这个
And you would only know that
是因为你真爱我
because you do love me!
亲爱的 怎么了
Hi, honey. What's up?
我只是想告诉你
Well, I just wanted to let you know
我拒绝了酒店的职位
I turned down that hotel job offer.
为什么
How come?
生活中有比钱更重要的东西
Some things are just more important than money,
对我来说那包括我的家...
and for me that includes my fam--
真疼
Man, that smarts.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
修修鼻毛
Just trimming the hedges.
我之前见到一张自己的仰角照
I saw a low-angle photo of me the other day.
看起来就像我鼻子里有个犹太传教士[大胡子]
I looked like a snorted a rabbi.
你 你拿着我的照片
And -- and -- and you're using
当你的镜子吗
a picture of me as your mirror?
真的是你诶
Oh, it is you!
那不是我的手机吗
Hey, is that my phone?
是的
Ah, yes!
我在你睡觉的时候找到的
I found it while you were asleep.
我先放回你的卧室 等你醒了再说吧
Um, let me put it back in your bedroom until you wake up.
凯莉给我发短信了
Oh, Kylie texted me.
她发来一张我和她的照片
She sent me a photo of me and her.
就坐在这
Sitting right here.
也许她是溜进来的
Oh, maybe she sneak in
在我去给你买那些东西的时候
while I was getting you all those nice stuff.
但你就在我们身后
But you're behind me,
用一种可怕的眼神盯着我们
staring at us with a terrible look on your face.
不可能 我照相都很注意
Oh, that's impossible. I never take a bad picture.
你是想破坏我和凯莉的关系吗
Are you trying to sabotage my relationship with Kylie?
她的衣服太紧身 她的鞋跟太高
Her clothes are too tight, her heels are too high,
她嗓门又大 而且
She's so loud, and --
而且我讨厌她管得你密不透风
And I hate how she smothers you!
天呐 你在说自己吗
Oh, my God. You're describing yourself.
不 我的衣服不算...
No! My clothes are not that...
我的鞋跟...
My heels are...
我也没那么吵
I am not... loud.
我在跟我妈约会
I'm dating my mother!
真恶心
Oh, gross.
你说什么
Excuse me?
我以前喜欢她 可现在都变了
I used to like her, but now it's ruined.
得了吧 还有比约会自己老妈更糟的呢
Please. There are worse things than dating your own mother.
比如说呢
Like what?
我不喜欢你这种态度
You know what? I don't like this attitude,
我相信凯莉也不会喜欢的
and I am sure that Kylie won't like it either.
也许你的确需要一个她那样的人
Maybe you do need somebody like her
当我不在的时候管着你
to keep you in line while I am not around.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我要把你的申请发给戏剧夏令营
I am sending your application to drama camp.
我们还有两分钟
We still have two minutes.
老妈 你休想
Mom, don't you dare.
名字 年龄...
Okay, name, age...
街道名[绰号] 黑帮里的那种外号吗
street name? Like you're in a gang?
我不想跟凯莉一起去夏令营了
I don't want to go to camp with Kylie now!
太恶心了
It's disgusting!
她又发短信来了
Oh, look. We got another text from Ky--
是一张她穿比基尼的照片
she send a picture of her in a bikini!
真的吗
She did?
那你还是把申请发过去吧
You -- you can just go ahead and hit "send".
别想了 你不能跟这种女孩去夏令营的
No. You're not going to go to camp with a girl like that.
我的天 老妈 你疯了
Oh, my God. Mom, you're crazy!
一会儿同意一会儿不同意
Yes. No. Yes. No.
你讨厌每一个和我约会的女孩
You hate every single girl I like.
你必须得让我自己做决定
You have to start letting me make my own decisions,
否则大家笑我的话都要成真了
or everything everybody says about me is true--
我就是个妈宝
I'm a giant mama's boy.
他们真的这么叫你吗
Do they really call you that?
没错 难道这就是你想看到的吗
Yes. Now is that what you want?
好吧
Okay, fine.
你想去的话 去吧
If you want to go, go.
谢谢
Thank you.
我也有那套比基尼
I have that same bikini.
我们需要一个撬杠或是什么
Okay, we're gonna need a crow bar
来把它弄起来
or something to lift this thing.
你在后面找找 我去架子上翻一翻
You look back there, and I'll check these shelves.
有能用的吗
Anything up there?
什么都没有
Not a thing, buddy.
我好像看见了某种...
I feel like I saw some sort of a--
他们知道吗
Are they aware...?
怎么可能知道
Not a chance.
也许可以用这个扫帚把它弄松
Maybe we can use this broom handle to pry it loose.
不行 弄不开的
No, that won't work. Oh, no.
可以弄开
Yes, it will.
来吧
Come on!
好险
That was close.
很抱歉之前对你那么刻薄
Sorry I was a jerk earlier.
又能和你一起看动画片
I'm actually having a lot of fun
我其实很开心
watching cartoons with you again.
是我的错 我就是有一点...
It was my fault. I'm just a little...
你以后会打电话给我吗
Are you ever gonna call me?
什么
What?
我一直
It's just something I've--
我一直在想
I've been wondering about, you know.
我们现在住在一起
Like, we live together,
所以你不用打电话给我
so you don't have to call me,
可是一旦你去了那所高智商学校
and once you're off at brainy school,
身边全是高智商的同学
surrounded by a bunch of brainy brains...
我们还会是朋友吗
are we gonna be friends?
你在说什么 你可是我姐姐
What are you talking about? You're my sister.
对啊 我们是姐妹
Oh, right. Yeah, sisters.
每个节假日我们都要看见对方 感恩节
Like, we're obligated to see each other on Thanksgiving,
圣诞节...
Christmas...
-卢克的葬礼 -我没事
- Luke's funeral. - I'm fine!
怎么了
"Uh-oh" what?
没事
Nothing.
你干了什么
What did you do?
我是听从你的指令
I was following your orders.
我很惊讶你居然没让我站在中间
I'm surprised you didn't ask me to stand on top
然后用锯子在我周围锯一个圈
and saw around myself in a circle.
我们要这个东西有什么用
Why do we even need this stupid thing?
因为他们要拆除我唯一建造过的东西
Because they're tearing down the only thing I've ever built.
站在那别动 我们能行
Just stand there. We can still do is.
当一名房地产中介挺好的
Yeah, it's great being a real estate agent,
我的脸被印在广告牌和笔上
my face is on billboards and pens.
我还有预算布置气球
I have a balloon budget.
但是那些都没办法永存
But none of it ever lasts.
一旦这地方被拆了
Once this place is gone,
就再也没有什么能让我指着说
they're won't be anything I can point to and say,
"这都归功于我"
"I made that."
-你干了什么 -你觉得呢
- What did you do? - What does it look like?!
我把水管弄坏了
I sprung a leak!
一定有阀门能关掉它的
There's gotta be a water shut-off!
海莉...
Haley...
如果我最近表现出来
I'm sorry if I've been acting like
不想跟你出去玩的样子 我很抱歉
I didn't wanna hang out with you lately.
我可能一直都这么表现
Or...ever.
别担心了
Don't worry about it.
我从没担心过
I'm not worried.
等我们不被关在一起
We'll probably be even closer
我们俩可能会更亲密
once we're not actually caged in together.
我会总打电话给你的
I'll be calling you all the time.
想想看
Think about it--
整个校园里都是艾丽克斯
I'm about to live on a campus full of Alexes.
一定会很让人抓狂的
That's bound to get annoying.
到时候除了你还能有谁帮我应付艾丽克斯
And when it does, who better to deal with an Alex than you?
这都归功于我
I made that.
你想见我
Hey, you wanted to see me?
-刚跟丹·希格诺打完电话 -谁
- Just got off the phone with Dan Signer. - Who?
他是皇家大酒店的大股东之一
He's one of the big mucks at the Grand Royal Hotels.
他们打算取消和我们的合作
They're thinking about dropping our account.
因为你拒绝了他们
Something about you turning down the job offer.
然后又接受
Well... and then accepting it,
然后又拒绝 接着又接受
and then turning it down, and then accepting it again.
你为什么要这样耍他
Why are you jerking him around?
你比克劳迪娅还糟糕
You're worse than Claudia.
-谁是克劳迪娅 -杰妮斯的前女友
- Who's claudia? - Janice's ex-girlfriend.
她把她骗了整整八年
She strung her along for eight years,
她们现在在为两只拉布拉多的监护权打官司
now they're in a custody battle over two Labradors.
难道今天我是唯一一个在休息室
Am I the only one that got stuck in the break room
听她诉苦的人吗
with her today?
老爸 如果能行
Okay, dad, look. If it'll help,
我会打给酒店的人 把这一切都说开
I'll call the hotel people and I'll straighten all this out.
我不觉得你再打电话去有什么用
I don't think more calls from you is the answer,
还有
and by the way,
我觉得你拿不到那份工作了
I don't think you're gonna get that job anymore.
行啊 我无所谓 我才不在乎呢
Fine! I don't care! I don't care!
我从一开始就没想要那份工作
I never wanted that job in the first place!
那你为什么一开始要跟我说呢
Well, then why did you tell me about it in the first place?
因为我想让你叫我别去做那份工作啊
Because I wanted you to tell me not to take the job
因为我是你女儿
Because I'm your daughter!
那面镜子后面的那个人
You know, the thing behind the mirror
就是你用来修鼻毛的那面镜子
that you...trim your nose hairs with?
你有在意过我的去留吗
Don't you even care if I stay or go?
我当然有
Of course I do.
好吧 可你没什么表示啊
Well, you don't show it.
也许是因为我不想让这影响到你的决定
Well, maybe because I didn't want that to be a factor.
一想到我的感受可能让你做不了
It would kill me if I thought that what I felt
你想做的事 我就会痛苦到不行
would hold you back from getting something that you wanted.
你要相信 当我看到那份工作邀请
But trust me, when I saw that job offer,
我紧张得心都快要跳出来
my heart almost fell out of my chest.
我很爱我们一起工作
I love us working together!
谢谢 那好吧
Thanks. Okay, then.
那好吧
"Okay, then"?
我掏心掏肺的 就得到这么一句话
I pour my heart out, and that's all I get?
有一次我爸跟我说了句"打得漂亮"
One time my dad said, "Nice game, kid."
我的防光黑彩跟着眼泪一起往下流
I had eye black streaming down my cheeks,
这一次我居然只得到一句"那好吧"
but all I get is, "Okay, then"?
好吧 可能我平时该说但没怎么说
I mean, I-I probably don't say it as much as I should,
但是我真的为你感到自豪 孩子
but I'm proud of you, kid.
我知道了
Got it.
-杰 -是丹啊
- Jay? - Hey, Dan!
天哪 我没想到您会亲自出现
Gee, I didn't think you'd show up in person.
克莱尔 这位就是重要人物丹·希格诺
Claire, this is the big cheese, Dan Signer.
您好 希格诺先生 很高兴认识您
Hi, Mr. Signer. Such a pleasure to meet you.
我为今天反反复复的态度向您道个歉
I'm so sorry about all that back and forth today.
行了 让我来
Hey, I'll handle it from here.
丹 我们很喜欢跟你们合作
Dan, we love doing business with you,
但是这事跟克莱尔有关 我得坚定一点
but I gotta put my foot down when it comes to Claire.
这是我的宝贝女儿
This is my little baby girl here.
我一天之中最美好的时光
The best part of my day is having a coffee
就是和她一起在休息室喝杯咖啡
with her in the break room,
而且这之前没多久
and it wasn't that long ago
她还坐在早餐桌前
that she was sitting at the breakfast table
吃着我给她做的心形华夫饼
eating heart-shaped waffles that I made for her.
我告诉你 这简直让人哽咽
I tell ya, it puts a lump in your throat.
不管怎么说吧
Anyway, uh,
我不知道我凭什么成了最幸运的家伙
I don't know how I got to be the luckiest S.O.B. alive...
但是只要我还有那么一点时日...
But if I have just even a few grains left in that hourglass...
我就想用来跟...
I'm gonna be spending it with...
我差点就把她的小名给说出来了
I almost just called her by her childhood nickname there.
管他呢
Ah, what the hell?
我的小福福兔宝宝
My little bunny foo-foo.
-哦别说了 -我送你出去吧 丹
- Oh, no. - Let me walk you out, Dan.
-兔宝宝 -感谢你的大驾光临
- Bunny! - Thanks for coming.
兔宝宝
Bunny!
谁是丹·希格诺
Who's Dan Signer?
我们不是要去俱乐部喝酒吗
I thought we were grabbing a beer at the club.
只管向前走 梅奥
Just keep walking, Mel.
那个 莉莉 你在忙吗
Uh, Lily, are you busy?
看情况
Depends.
我们想聊一聊关于感受的话题
Well, we wanted to have a little talk about feelings.
好吧 其实我明天得交这份作业
Oh, actually, I have this project due tomorrow --
好吧 亲爱的 收起来 没关系的
Okay, honey. No, no. It's okay. It's okay.
坐下来
Let's just sit down.
听着 我们只想问你觉不觉得我哭太多
Listen, we just wanted to ask if you think I cry too much.
你可以说实话
And you can be honest.
我不太想回答 不然你可能又要哭
I don't want to answer 'cause you might cry.
好吧
Yeah, well...
她是在乎我的感受的
She cares about my feelings!
莉莉 我们觉得你不爱表达感情
Okay, Lily, we think that maybe you don't get emotional
是因为大爸太多愁善感
because daddy gets, you know, so emotional
因为他基本上扛起了
because he kind of handles
-整个家的情绪 -确实
- the emotions for the entire house, you know? - I do.
-可能是整个街区 -好吧
- Possibly the entire block. - Okay.
可能因此你没有什么感情
And maybe that's why you don't feel anything.
我有啊
I feel stuff.
是吗 因为几周前 我们俩病了
Really? Because when we were sick a few weeks ago,
你好像不怎么关心
You didn't seem to care.
我是不关心啊
I didn't care.
她没撒谎 我们起码做对了点事
Well, she's not a liar. We did something right.
你不觉得你应该至少关心一下下吗
Don't you think you should have cared a little bit?
为什么 反正你们都是会好起来的啊
Why? You always get better.
好吧 以后就不一定了
Well... so far.
"以后就不一定了"是什么意思
What do you mean, "So far"?
呃 这个嘛
Um... well, uh...
就是说有一天你们会好不起来了吗
Like someday, you're not gonna get better?
你们会死吗
Like you're gonna die?
不是 不不 很长时间内都不会的
No! No, no, no, no. Not, not for a very, very long time.
那我们为什么现在要讨论这个
Then why are we talking about it now?
是你先挑起来的好吧
Well, hey, you brought it up.
我只是想确认一下
I just wanted to make sure that --
别说了 你们说得我好难过
Stop! You're making me sad!
好吧 她是有感情的
Okay, well, she has feelings.
是啊 而且看起来她希望我们活着
Well, yes, and it seems that she wants to keep us alive.
总而言之 今天的教育还是很成功的
So all in all, a good day of parenting.
我不要跟克莱尔姨妈住
I don't want to live with aunt Claire!
莉莉
Lily!
父母在教育子女时总是犯很多错...
Parents make so many mistakes with their children...
我还活着 亲爱的
I've alive, sweetheart.
可是大爸呢
But what about daddy?
我也还活着
I'm alive, too.
过来 来吧 宝贝
Come here. Come on, sweetheart.
但这也只是因为我们竭尽全力
But it's only because we're trying so hard
想让他们过得快乐
to make them happy.
她不行 她不行 我的天
Not her. Not her. Oh, my God.
你要成为整所学校最漂亮的女孩了
You're gonna be the cutest girl at this whole school.
等等 这些是女孩子吧
Wait, these are girls, right?
竭尽全力把他们留在身边...
Trying so hard to keep them close...
你该敲下门的
You could knock.
尽管知道总有一天留不住
even though we know we can't.
我知道将来我要把你交到别的女人手上
I know someday I'm gonna lose you to another woman,
但是我会想办法接受的
and I'll find a way to be okay with it.
谢谢你 凯莉
Thanks, Kylie.
但今天不会
But not today.
接着我走进他的办公室
So, I walk into his office
他在看我的照片
he's looking at a picture of me
而且在哭
and he's crying.
你爸吗
Your dad?
是啊 我都不敢相信
Yeah, I couldn't believe it either.
这也是为何我很乐意在女儿面前
This is why I'm glad that I show my emotions
表达我的感受
in front of the girls.
-我觉得这就是为什么... -菲尔
- I think that's the reason that feeling... - Phill,
我们能不能在炉子热起来之前
can we at least have my story
先听完我的故事
until the oven preheats?
对不起 我以为你说完了
Sorry, I thought you were finished.
好吧 后来我又去了一趟他的办公室
Okay, so, anyway, I went back later and it turns out
原来他没有在哭
he wasn't crying,
他是在拔他的鼻毛
he was plucking his nose hairs.
我可没想到
I didn't expect that.
是啊 我也想不到
Yeah, me neither.
能走进那间影院
To walk into that theatre and see
然后看着她们的小脑袋靠在一起
their cute little heads together
就在她们吵了一下午的架之后
after they had been fighting all afternoon.
拜托 你刚才绝对算是说完了
Come on, you had to be done that time.
没有 这是我的问题吗
No, is it me?
是我讲故事的方式有问题吗
Is it the way that I tell stories?
是我太闷还是这个家里的所有人
Am I so boring or is everyone in this family
就只关心自己
that self-involved.
接着我刚没说完的
As I was saying
她叫埃莲娜 来自北卡罗莱纳州
Her name was Elena and she's from North Carolina.
这就是我的室友
That's my roomate.
现在我说完了
Now I'm done.